https://fabric-direct.co.uk/privacy-policy/

Hole In The Wall Curtains Ltd
(fabric-direct.co.uk)
Privacy policy
Introduction
1.1    We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our website visitors and service users.
1.2    This policy applies where we are acting as a data controller with respect to the personal data of our website visitors and service users; in other words, where we determine the purposes and means of the processing of that personal data.
1.3    In this policy, “we”, “us” and “our” refer to Hole In The Wall Curtains Limited, we are the owner and operator of this website (fabric-direct.co.uk). For more information about us, see Section 12.
How we use your personal data
2.1    In this Section 2 we have set out:
(a)    the general categories of personal data that we may process;
(b)    the purposes for which we may process personal data; and
(d)    the legal bases of the processing.
2.2    We may process data about your use of our website and services (“usage data“). The usage data may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your service use. The source of the usage data is Google Analytics and WordPress. This usage data may be processed for the purposes of analysing the use of the website and services. The legal basis for this processing is consent OR our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services.
2.3    We may process your account data (“account data“). The account data may include your name, email address, telephone number and postal address. The source of the account data is you. The account data may be processed for the purposes of operating our website, providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases, communicating with you, offering, marketing and selling relevant goods and/or services to you. The legal basis for this processing is consent OR our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business OR the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract.
2.4    We may process information contained in any enquiry you submit to us regarding goods and/or services (“enquiry data“). The enquiry data may be processed for the purposes of offering, marketing and selling relevant goods and/or services to you. The legal basis for this processing is consent OR the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract.
2.5    We may process information relating to transactions, including purchases of goods and services, that you enter into with us and/or through our website (“transaction data“). The transaction data may include your contact details, your payment card details and the transaction details. The transaction data may be processed for the purpose of supplying the purchased goods and services and keeping proper records of those transactions. The legal basis for this processing is the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract and our legitimate interests, namely our interest in the proper administration of our website and business.
2.6    We may process information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our email notifications and/or newsletters (“notification data“). The notification data may be processed for the purposes of sending you the relevant notifications and/or newsletters, the purposes of offering, marketing and selling relevant goods and/or services to you. The legal basis for this processing is consent OR the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract.
2.7    We may process information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us (“correspondence data“). The correspondence data may include the communication content and metadata associated with the communication. Our website will generate the metadata associated with communications made using the website contact forms. The correspondence data may be processed for the purposes of communicating with you, record-keeping and, the purposes of offering, marketing and selling relevant goods and/or services to you. The legal basis for this processing is consent OR our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business and communications with users.
2.8    We may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the protection and assertion of our legal rights, your legal rights and the legal rights of others.
2.9    We may process any of your personal data identified in this policy where necessary for the purposes of obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, or obtaining professional advice. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper protection of our business against risks.
2.10  In addition to the specific purposes for which we may process your personal data set out in this Section 2, we may also process any of your personal data where such processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.
2.11  Please do not supply any other person’s personal data to us.
Providing your personal data to others
3.1    We may disclose your personal data to any member of our group of companies (this means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and all its subsidiaries) as far as is reasonably necessary for the purposes, and on the legal bases, set out in this policy.
3.2    We may disclose your personal data to our insurers and/or professional advisers as far as is reasonably necessary for the purposes of obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, obtaining professional advice, or the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.
3.3    We may disclose your enquiry data to our variable suppliers or subcontractors (identifiable on request) as far as is reasonably necessary to assist our marketing and sales activities. Your enquiry data may be uploaded to and held by a secure account with Mailchimp for the purposes of distributing our newsletters, marketing and sales information. Mailchimp’s privacy policy can be found here. We may upload your enquiry data to Facebook in order to identify a Facebook ‘Personal Profile’ associated with your data for the purposes of marketing and sales via Facebook’s advertising platform. This is only possible where you have already submitted your personal data to Facebook and only possible where the personal data you have submitted to us is identical to the personal data you have already submitted to Facebook. Facebook’s privacy policy can be found here.
3.4    Financial transactions relating to our website and services may be handled by our payment services providers; Paypal, Stripe, SagePay, Woo Commerce and our payment card merchant provider. We will share transaction data with our payment services providers only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing your payments, refunding such payments and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments and refunds.
3.5    In addition to the specific disclosures of personal data set out in this Section 3, we may disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. We may also disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.
Retaining and deleting personal data
5.1    This Section 5 sets out our data retention policies and procedure, which are designed to help ensure that we comply with our legal obligations in relation to the retention and deletion of personal data.
5.2    Personal data that we process for any purpose or purposes shall not be kept for longer than is necessary for that purpose or those purposes.
5.4    We will determine the period of data retention based on the following criteria:
(a)    the period of retention of enquiry data, notification data and correspondence data, will be determined based on the period between consent being given and consent being withdrawn. If consent is withdrawn then enquiry data, notification data and correspondence data will be deleted.
(b)    Where personal data is held for the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract AND you have consented then the period of retention of personal data will be determined based on the period between consent being given and consent being withdrawn. If consent is withdrawn, then personal data will be deleted.
(c)    Where personal data is held for the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract AND you have not consented then the period of retention of personal data will be determined based on the current legal requirement to maintain transactional records. Once that period has elapsed then personal data will be deleted.
5.5    Notwithstanding the other provisions of this Section 5, we may retain your personal data where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.
Amendments
6.1    We may update this policy from time to time by publishing a new version on our website.
6.2    You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes to this policy.
6.3    We may notify you of changes to this policy by email.
Your rights
7.1    In this Section 7, we have summarised the rights that you have under data protection law. Some of the rights are complex, and not all of the details have been included in our summaries. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights.
7.2    Your principal rights under data protection law are:
(a)    the right to access;
(b)    the right to rectification;
(c)    the right to erasure;
(d)    the right to restrict processing;
(e)    the right to object to processing;
(f)    the right to data portability;
(g)    the right to complain to a supervisory authority; and
(h)    the right to withdraw consent.
7.3    You have the right to confirmation as to whether or not we process your personal data and, where we do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information. That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, we will supply to you a copy of your personal data. The first copy will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee. You can request copies of your personal data by e-mailing enquiries@holeinthewallcurtains.co.uk
7.4    You have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you completed.
7.5    In some circumstances you have the right to the erasure of your personal data without undue delay. Those circumstances include: the personal data is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing purposes; and the personal data have been unlawfully processed. However, there are exclusions of the right to erasure. The general exclusions include where processing is necessary: for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information; for compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.
7.6    In some circumstances you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Those circumstances are: you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is unlawful but you oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal data for the purposes of our processing, but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection. Where processing has been restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your personal data. However, we will only otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person; or for reasons of important public interest.
7.7    You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that the processing is necessary for: the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of any official authority vested in us; or the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process the personal information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.
7.8    You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes (including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose.
7.9    You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes on grounds relating to your particular situation, unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out for reasons of public interest.
7.10  To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal data is:
(a)    consent; or
(b)    that the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract,
and such processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your personal data from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.
7.11  If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your habitual residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.
7.12  To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of processing before the withdrawal.
7.13  You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by written notice to us by e-mailing enquiries@holeinthewallcurtains.co.uk in addition to the other methods specified in this Section 7.
About cookies
8.1    A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.
8.2    Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.
8.3    Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.
Cookies that we use
9.1    We use cookies for the following purpose:
Analysis – we use cookies to help us to analyse the use and performance of our website and services (cookies used for this purpose are: persistent cookies.
Cookies used by our service providers
10.1  Our service providers use cookies and those cookies may be stored on your computer when you visit our website.
10.2  We use Google Analytics to analyse the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google’s privacy policy is available at: https://www.google.com/policies/privacy
Managing cookies
11.1  Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:
(a)    https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en (Chrome);
(b)    https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences (Firefox);
(c)    http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/ (Opera);
(d)    https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies (Internet Explorer);
(e)    https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411 (Safari); and
(f)    https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy (Edge).
11.2  Blocking all cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites.
11.3  If you block cookies, you will normally still be able to use all of the features on our website.
Our details
12.1  This website (fabric-direct.co.uk) is owned and operated by Hole In The Wall Curtains Limited.
12.2  We are registered in England and Wales under registration number 05108280, and our registered office is at: 47-49 Goodall Street, Walsall, West Midlands WS1 1QJ
12.3  Our principal place of business is at 47-49 Goodall Street, Walsall, West Midlands WS1 1QJ
12.4  You can contact us:
(a)    by post, to 47-49 Goodall Street, Walsall, West Midlands WS1 1QJ
(b)    using our website contact form;
(c)    by telephone, on 01922 631512
(from abroad +44 1922 631512)
(d)    by email, using enquiries@holeinthewallcurtains.co.uk
Data protection officer
13.1  Our data protection officer’s contact details are:
The Data Protection Officer,
47-49 Goodall Street,
Walsall,
West Midlands
WS1 1QJ
In The Sale
Garnet Diamond Curtain Fabric BR537
£49.75 £24.99 per metre
Amethyst Stripe Curtain Fabric BR536
£14.50 £7.99 per metre
Coffee Rose Curtain Fabric BR535
£89.00 – £536.00
'Carnival Mauve' Belfield Design Studio - Made To Measure Curtains
£82.00 – £487.00
'Lewis Yellow' Belfield Design Studio Made To Measure Curtains
£87.00 – £520.00
My Basket
Orders
Track Your Order
Lost password
Terms & Conditions
Privacy Policy
From The Blog
04
Dec
The Great British Sewing Bee Christmas Special
0 comments
24
Nov
Black Friday Bargains!!
0 comments
13
Nov
Everyone Needs a Hero!
0 comments
Shop Securely:Our Stores:
© Copyright 2020 - Fabric Direct Online / Hole In The Wall Curtains Group Ltd
×
MenuHomeDressDress FabricDress FabricsBroderie AnglaiseBudget Polyester SatinChildren’s DesignsChristmas FabricCotton 100%Cotton DrillDC ComicsDenimDisneyDress LiningDress NetDupionFlannelFleeceGinghamHalloweenHarry PotterJerseyKlona CottonLaceLinen-LookLicensed MaterialsLycraMarvelNoveltyPlain ViscosePolycotton PatternsPolycotton PlainPolyesterPoplinPoplin SpotQuiltingRipstopSatinScubaSequinSummer PatternsTartanTowellingTulleVelourVelvetWinter FabricsPrintsAnimal PrintAnimalsButterfliesCamouflageChecksChevronChildrens Dress FabricDinosaursFloralFruitHeartsHounds ToothMusicNauticalNoveltyPaisleyPlaidPolka DotsSkullsStarsStripesUnicornsBy ColourColoursYellowBlueTurquoisePurplePinkWhiteBlackGreyRedOrangeNavy BlueBurgundySilverGoldCreamMulti-ColouredLilacIvoryGreenBrownBridal FabricBridal FabricsSatin Bridal FabricTulleHologram TulleTwinkle TulleKnotted OrganzaEvening Dress FabricEvening WearAll Over SequinBudget LaceCorded LaceKnotted OrganzaSilk TouchVelour CrushedDance FabricDanceCarnivalLycra Dance FabricMetallic Dress Net Dance FabricPaper Lame Dance FabricStretch MaterialSequin Dance FabricCraft FabricsFabric For CraftingFeltFurQuiltingFabric For QuiltingPrice Per MetrePrice Per Metre£0.00 To: £4.99£5.00 To: £9.99£10.00 To: £19.99£20.00 To: £29.99CurtainStylesCurtain Fabric FinderAfricanAztecBrocadeCheckChenilleChildrensCorduroyDamaskDraylonEmbroideriesFloralGeometricHerringboneJacquardsLeafPatternedPlainPrintedRetroSheers & VoilesSilks & TaffetasStripedSuedeTartanTweedVelourVelvetVintageWoolsWovenBrandsBrandsAshley WildeBelfield Design StudioBill BeaumontChatham GlynnClarke & ClarkeFryettsHardyHarlequinILIVPorter & StonePrestigiousRomoSandersonScionSMDStyle FurnishingsVilla NovaVoyageWilliam MorrisColoursColoursBeigeBlackBlueBrownCreamGoldGreenGreyMulti-ColouredNaturalsPinkPurpleRedTerracottaWhiteWineOrangeYellowAccessoriesTie BacksLining & SundriesLining & SundriesCurtain LiningInterliningThreadsCurtain TapeWorkroom EssentialsPrice Per MetrePrice Per Metre£0.00 To: £4.99£5.00 To: £9.99£10.00 To: £19.99£20.00 To: £29.99£30.00 To: £39.99£40.00 To: £49.99Made To MeasureBrandsAll BrandsAshley WildeBelfield Design StudioChatham GlynnClarke & ClarkeFryettsHardyHarlequinILIVJim DickensPrestigiousRomoSandersonSMDVilla NovaVoyageWilliam MorrisStylesAll StylesAfricanAztecBrocadeCheckChenilleChildrensCorduroyDamaskDraylonEmbroideriesFloralGeometricHerringboneJacquardsLeafPatternedPlainPrintedRetroSheers & VoilesSilks & TaffetasStripedSuedeTartanTweedVelourVelvetVintageWoolsWovenColoursColoursBeigeBlackBlueBrownCreamGoldGreenGreyMulticolouredNaturalsPinkPurpleRedTerracottaWhiteWineOrangeYellowUpholsteryStylesUpholstery Fabric FinderAztecAfricanBrocadeCheckChenilleCorduroyDamaskDraylonFloralGeometricHerringboneLeafPatternedPlainRetroStripedSuede EffectTartanTweedVelourVelvetVintageWovenColourColourBeigeBlackBlueBrownCreamGoldGreenGreyMulti-ColouredNaturalsPinkPurpleRedTerracottaWhiteWineOrangeYellowSundriesSundriesBacking ClothHessianPre Cut FoamSpraysStaple Guns & GunsStudsWebbingWaddingThreadPrice Per MetrePrice Per Metre£0.00 To: £4.99£5.00 To: £9.99£10.00 To: £19.99£20.00 To: £29.99£30.00 To: £39.99£40.00 To: £49.99CraftTypeTypeAida & BincaBeads & SequinsCork VinylCotton Craft FabricCraft AccessoriesCraft ToolsFeltFurGlues & AdhesivesLinenPaints & DyesPipe CleanersPom PomsToy MakingColoursColoursBlueBrownBurgundyCreamGoldGreenGreyWhiteBlackTurquoiseLilacPurpleNavy BluePinkMulti ColouredRedOrangeYellowIvorySilverPricePrice£0.00 To: £4.99£5.00 To: £9.99£10.00 To: £19.99£20.00 To: £29.99QuiltingQuilting FabricQuilting Fabric100% Cotton60 Inch WideBasics & BlendersExtra WideJohn LoudenKlona CottonMakowerPanelsPatternedPlainPoplinRose and HubbleAccessoriesAccessoriesAdhesivesBatting/WaddingMarking ToolsNeedles & ThreadersPinsScissorsSewing Machine AccessoriesStabiliers & FusiblesTape MeasuresThimblesThreadsDesignsDesignsAnimal PrintAnimalsBasics & BlendersBatiksCat and DogChildren’s DesignsChristmas FabricDC ComicsDisneyHalloweenHarry PotterHeartsMarvelNoveltySpotStar WarsUnicorn & Fairy TaleColoursColoursBlackBlueBrownBurgundyCreamGoldGreenGreyIvoryLilacWhiteTurquoisePurpleNavy BluePinkMulti ColouredRedOrangeYellowSilverPricePrice£0.00 To: £4.99£5.00 To: £9.99£10.00 To: £19.99KnittingSuppliesSuppliesAccessoriesCrochetKitsNeedles & HooksPatternsYarnColoursColoursBlackBlueBrownBurgundyCreamGoldGreenGreyIvoryWhiteTurquoiseLilacPurpleNavy BluePinkMulti ColouredRedYellowSilverOrangePricePrice£0.00 To: £4.99£5.00 To: £9.99HaberdasheryAll ItemsAll ItemsBag HandlesBinding, Cords & TapesBobbinsButtonsElasticFastenersGlue, Cleaners & ProtectorsLaceMarking ToolsNeedles ThreadersPinsRepair & MaintenanceRibbonScissorsSewing EssentialsSewing Machine AccessoriesTape MeasuresThimblesThreadsTrimmingsWaddingWebbingZips & FastenersAdhesivesPricePrice£0.00 To: £4.99£5.00 To: £9.99£10.00 To: £19.99ClearanceClearance FabricClearance FabricClearance Curtain FabricClearance Dress FabricClearance Tie BacksClearance Upholstery FabricMiscellaneousColourColoursBlackBlueBrownBurgundyCreamGreyWhiteGreenTurquoiseLilacPurpleNavy BluePinkMulti ColouredRedOrangeYellowIvoryCreamGoldSilverPrice Per MetrePrice Per Metre£0.00 To: £4.99£5.00 To: £9.99£10.00 To: £19.99£20.00 To: £29.99£30.00 To: £39.99£40.00 To: £49.99Eco Friendly Fabric
Blog
FAQs
Gift Cards
Contact Us
Buying Fabric With Klarna
×
What are you looking for?
Search for:
This site uses cookies and protects your data in line with the GDPR. Read more here:
Privacy & Cookie PolicyOkay, thank you
